(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
HAACHAMA WORLD
あたし、タランチャマ！
I'm Taranchama!
蜘蛛人間なの！
I'm a spider human!
お前を食っちゃうぞ〜〜！
I'm gonna eat you up!
うふふ！だめだよ〜〜！
Tee-hee! No way!
ずっとみんな、なかよし！
Everyone, friends forever!
うふふ、やくそくだよ？
Hehe, it's a promise, okay?
あなたは今どこで何をしていますか？
Where are you now, and what are you doing?
この空の続く場所にいますか？
Are you at a place where this sky continues to?
今まで私の心を埋めていたもの
The things that had filled my heart until now
失って初めて気づいた
I only realized after losing them
こんなにも私を支えてくれていたこと
That they were supporting me so much
こんなにも笑顔をくれていたこと
That they were giving me so many smiles
失ってしまった代償は
The price of having lost them
とてつもなく大きすぎて
Is unimaginably huge
取り戻そうと必死に
Desperately trying to take them back
手を伸ばしてもがくけれど
I reach out my hand and struggle, but
まるで風のようにすり抜けて
They slip away just like the wind
届きそうで届かない
Looking reachable but out of reach
孤独と絶望に胸を締め付けられ
My chest is tightened by loneliness and despair
心が壊れそうになるけれど
My heart feels like it's about to break, but
思い出に残るあなたの笑顔が
Your smile remaining in my memories
私をいつも励ましてくれる
Always encourages me
もう一度あの頃に戻ろう
Let's go back to those days once again
今度はきっと大丈夫
This time, it'll surely be okay
いつもそばで笑っていよう
Let's always be laughing by each other's side
あなたのすぐそばで
Right by your side
あなたは今どこで何をしていますか？
Where are you now, and what are you doing?
夢の続く場所にいますか
Are you in a place where the dream continues?
いつものように笑顔でいてくれますか
Will you keep smiling like you always do?
今はただそれを願い続ける
For now, I'll just keep wishing for that.
生誕ライブ限定グッズ販売のお知らせ！
Announcement of limited birthday live merchandise!
家族写真B2タペストリー
Family Photo B2 Tapestry
ゴージャスな額縁風デザインと肖像画のような二人がとってもキュート。
The gorgeous frame-like design and the portrait-like duo are so cute.
お部屋の壁に、今日の思い出を飾って彩り豊かな推し活ができちゃいます。
Decorate your wall with today's memories for a colorful fan life.
おでかけちゃまぬいぐるみ
Outing-Chama Plushie
ボタン風の目がとっても可愛いぬいぐるみ。
A plushie with very cute button-like eyes.
丁寧にひとつひとつ再現されたドレス衣装のちゃまと一緒におでかけして旅に出れちゃいます！
You can go out on a journey with Chama, whose dress outfit is meticulously reproduced!
鞄に付けれるハートチャーム付き。
Comes with a heart charm that can be attached to your bag.
タランちゃまぬいぐるみポーチ
Taran-Chama Plushie Pouch
あの...タランちゃまがポーチに！
That... Taran-Chama is now a pouch!
背中のファスナーが開いて収納できる便利アイテム。
A convenient item with a zipper on the back for storage.
ゴスロリ衣装のタランちゃまが可愛すぎる！
Taran-Chama in a Gothic Lolita outfit is too cute!
チェーンがついてるから安心してお外にお散歩させられるよ！
It has a chain, so you can safely take it out for a walk!
タランちゃまスマホリング
Taran-Chama Smartphone Ring
スマホの落下はタランちゃまにお任せ！
Leave preventing your phone from falling to Taran-Chama!
しっかり張り付いて守ってくれます。
It sticks firmly and protects it.
愛くるしいお目目と、つい目が合っちゃう瞬間も癒やされてたまりません。
The adorable eyes and the moments you accidentally lock eyes are irresistibly healing.
全部セットは数量限定もあります。
The full set is also available in limited quantities.
フルセット購入特典の数量限定バージョンは、箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードと、赤井はあと直筆サイン、特典ボイス『ひみつのはなし』もあるよ。
The limited quantity version of the full set bonus includes a foil-stamped postcard, a signed autograph, and a bonus voice clip 'A Secret Story'.
プロモカードもあるよ！
There's also a promo card!
hololive公式ECサイトで販売中！
On sale now at the Hololive official EC site!
ひとつだけ、ただひとつだけ見つけたものは
One thing, just one thing I found was
誠実で不器用な、
A sincere and clumsy,
それでも柔らかな声
yet soft voice
朽ちてゆき、ただ崩れゆく、
Rotting away, simply crumbling away,
世界を照らす
illuminating the world
暖かで、でも残酷な、
A warm, yet cruel,
去り際の笑顔
smile upon departure
ひび割れてゆく翡翠の水槽を満たすもの
Something filling the cracking jade aquarium
「永遠ではない」なんて、
Even though I knew,
初めから解ってたのに
from the start that 'it's not forever'
壊れても、なお美しく、
What carves into my heart,
胸を刻むのは
still beautiful even if broken
砕けても、なお美しい、
A single petal of memory,
ひとひらの記憶
still beautiful even if shattered
忘れたいのに、なお狂おしく、
Though I want to forget, still maddeningly,
胸に残るのは
what remains in my heart
痛みさえ忘れさせた、
The faint touch that made me,
微かな感触
forget even the pain
ひとつだけ、ただひとつだけ
The one thing,
伝えたのは
just one thing I conveyed was
冷たさで誤魔化した、
A desperate lie,
苦し紛れの嘘
disguised with coldness
愛しくて、ただ愛しくて、
Because you're dear, just so dear,
選んだ言葉は
the words I chose were
すべて終わらせる偽りのセリフ
False lines to bring everything to an end
風が吹けば飛ぶような砂に残した手紙
A letter left in the sand that would fly away if the wind blew
「永遠ではない」という事さえ忘れたのに...
Even though I forgot even the fact that 'it's not forever'...
「永遠ではない」という事さえ忘れられたのに…
Even though I'd forgotten that "nothing is forever"...
もう一度、もう一度と、もう何度思ったでしょう
"One more time, just one more time" — how many times have I thought that?
枯れた花束、捨てられもせず
A withered bouquet, unable to be thrown away.
降り止まぬ雨は、まるで万雷の拍手喝采
The ceaseless rain is like a thunderous round of applause.
愚かな後悔を、嗤う怒濤のよう
Like a surging wave laughing at my foolish regrets.
壊れても、なお美しく、胸を刻むのは
Even if broken, what still beautifully etches itself into my heart is...
砕けても、なお美しい、ひとひらの記憶
Even if shattered, what's still beautiful is a single petal of memory.
忘れたいのに、なお狂おしく、胸に残るのは
Even though I want to forget, what remains madly in my heart is...
痛みさえ忘れさせた、微かな感触
That faint touch that made me forget even the pain.
痛みさえ忘れさせた
It made me forget even the pain.
微かな感触
That faint touch.
「なんで…いなくなっちゃうの…」
"Why... are you leaving...?"
「こんなの苦しいよ…」
"This is so painful..."
「そばにいて…！」
"Stay with me...!"
「いつも、そばにいるよ。」
"I'm always by your side."
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've already forgotten.
夏の木陰に座ったまま、アイスを口に放り込んで風を待っていた
Sitting in the shade of a tree in summer, tossing ice cream into our mouths while waiting for the breeze.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've already forgotten.
世の中の全部嘘だらけ、本当の価値を二人で探しに行こうと笑ったこと
How we laughed about the world being full of lies, and decided to go find the true meaning together.
忘れないように
So that I don't forget.
色褪せないように
So that it doesn't fade away.
形に残るものが全てじゃないように
So that we know things with physical forms aren't everything.
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words.
夏が来るって教えて
Tell me that summer is coming.
僕は描いてる、眼に映ったのは夏の亡霊だ
I'm drawing; what appeared in my eyes was a ghost of summer.
風にスカートが揺れて
Your skirt fluttering in the wind.
思い出なんて忘れて
Forgetting all about memories.
浅い呼吸をする、汗を拭って夏めく
Taking shallow breaths, wiping away sweat, feeling the summer.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've already forgotten.
夏の木陰に座った頃、遠くの丘から顔出した雲があったじゃないか
That time we sat in the shade, and a cloud peeked out from the distant hill?
君はそれを掴もうとして、馬鹿みたいに空を切った手で
You tried to grab it, your hands foolishly cutting through the air.
僕は紙に雲一つを書いて、笑って握って見せて
I drew a single cloud on paper and showed it to you with a smile.
忘れないように
So that I don't forget.
色褪せないように
So that it doesn't fade away.
歴史に残るものが全てじゃないから
Because things that remain in history aren't everything.
今だけ顔も無くして
Losing even our faces just for now.
言葉も全部忘れて
Forgetting all our words.
君は笑ってる、夏を待ってる僕ら
You're laughing; we are waiting for summer.
花に亡霊 僕ら亡霊
Spirits in flowers, we are spirits
心をもっと教えて
Tell me more about your heart
夏の匂いを教えて
Tell me about the scent of summer
浅い呼吸をする
Taking shallow breaths
忘れないように
So I don't forget
色褪せないように
So it doesn't fade
心に響くものが全てじゃないから
Because things that resonate in the heart aren't everything
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words
さよならだって教えて
Teach me even about "goodbye"
今も見るんだよ 夏に咲いてる花に亡霊を
I still see it now, the spirits in the flowers blooming in summer
言葉じゃなくて時間を
Not words, but time
時間じゃなくて心を
Not time, but the heart
浅い呼吸をする
Taking shallow breaths
汗を拭って 夏めく
Wiping away sweat, it's becoming summer-like
夏の匂いがする
I can smell summer
もう忘れてしまったかな 夏の木陰に座ったまま
I wonder if you've already forgotten, while still sitting in the summer shade
アイスを口に放り込んで 風を待っていた
Popping ice cream into our mouths, waiting for the breeze
ということで、
And so...
赤井はあと爆誕祭2025
Akai Haato Birthday Festival 2025...
始まっちゃいます！
...is starting!
始まっちゃいまーす！
It's starting!
1曲目、1曲目まだ！
First song, the first song is still...!
体力温存しないと。
Need to save my energy.
ゲストに来てくれたのは...
The guest who came is...
らでんちゃん！
Raden-chan!
こんばんはー！ホロライブデバイス、
Good evening! I'm Juufuutei Raden from
ReGLOSSの儒烏風亭らでんでございまーす！
Hololive DEV_IS, ReGLOSS!
ありがとう、来てくれて！
Thank you for coming!
はあちゃま、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Haachama, happy birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
そして、新衣装じゃないですか！
And, isn't that a new outfit!
そうなの！キラキラ、
That's right! It's sparkly
かわいい！
and cute!
いや、この衣装めっちゃシナジーある！
Wow, this outfit has so much synergy!
なんからでんちゃん言ってたけど、
Like Raden-chan was saying,
これクリスマスカラーだよね、二人。
we're in Christmas colors, the two of us.
そうなのー！
That's right!
らでんはクリスマスツリー。
Raden is the Christmas tree.
と、はあちゃまは...
And, Haachama is...
サンタ！
Santa!
サンタです！
I'm Santa!
サンタ！ね、この季節にぴったり。
Santa! Right, perfect for this season.
お、ぴったりですね。
Oh, it is perfect.
夏を、夏の匂いがしますね。
Summer, it smells like summer.
ぴったり... 夏！
Perfect... Summer!
全然関係ねーだろ、今！
That has nothing to do with it right now!
クリスマスだと思ってんだよ。
I thought it was Christmas.
それもね、はあちゃま、
Also, for Akai Haato
赤井はあと爆誕祭2025でね。
Birthday Festival 2025...
ぜひともSNSでスクショとかツイートしてください！
...please post screenshots and tweets on social media!
してください！
Please do!
お願いしまーす！
Please!
じゃあなんか写真撮ろうか！
Let's take some photos then!
ぜひ撮りましょう。
Let's definitely take some.
お淑やかなポーズ行きますか、
Should we do a graceful pose,
せっかくなので。
since we're here?
決めたポーズ。
The decided pose.
お淑やかなポーズ。
Graceful pose.
二人、いいんじゃない？
Aren't we two looking good?
ホロライブ！
Hololive!
はあ！
Ha!
ハートで！今時な。
With a heart! A trendy one.
ハートで！いいじゃないっすか！
With a heart! Isn't that great!
あ、可愛い！
Ah, cute!
ハート！
Heart!
らでんちゃん大丈夫か！？
Raden-chan, are you okay!?
戻ってきて、戻ってきて！
Come back, come back!
もう、うちらの中じゃないっすか！
Jeez, we're friends, aren't we!
今のはね、
That was,
今のは喝入れただけだから！
that was just me giving you some encouragement!
そう、喝入れられました。
Yes, I was encouraged.
まずいまずいまずい、そんな。
Oh no, oh no, oh no.
殴ったりとかしないからね、
I'm not going to hit you or anything,
別に。
really.
しっとり。次曲歌わないと。
Calmly. Need to sing the next song.
ハートですからね。
We are "Haato" after all.
しゃなりと。
Gracefully.
しゃなりとね。
Gracefully, yes.
みんなスクショ撮ってくれてるか！
Is everyone taking screenshots!
撮ってくれてるのか！
Are you taking them!
もう、そんなわけで。
Well, so that's that.
今回ですね、我々は...
This time, we are...
なんか、ホロライブ。
...well, Hololive.
そうですよ、我々ユニット名
That's right, our unit name is
「ホロライブ」ですから、
"Hololive", so
覚えてくださいね。
please remember that.
いつのできたの？
When did that happen?
なんかだいぶ前に。
A while ago, apparently.
ユニット名「ホロライブ」って感じでね、
With the unit name "Hololive",
らでんちゃんとお送りしてきました。
I've been presenting this with Raden-chan.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
あの衣装も、シナジーがあるってわけで。
Our outfits also had some synergy.
『花に亡霊』をね、歌ったんですけども、どうでした？
We sang "Ghost in a Flower", how was it?
エモ！
So emotional!
このステージもすっごい合ってたし。
This stage really suited it as well.
やっぱりね、らでんちゃんに歌ってほしいパートがあったんですよ、やっぱ。
As I thought, there was a part I really wanted Raden-chan to sing.
どこどこ？
Which part?
『歴史に残るものだけが全てじゃない』っていうところで。
"It's not just about what remains in history."
あ、これちょっとらでんちゃんに歌ってほしいなと思って、掛け合いを分けさせてもらいました。
I thought, "Ah, I want Raden-chan to sing this," so I split the duet parts like that.
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
らでもどっかで歌いたいなーっていう曲だったから。
It was a song that I also wanted to sing somewhere.
そう、あの話一緒に歌いたいんだって言ってくれた時、『えっ、めっちゃ嬉しい！』と思って、良かった...
Yeah, when you said you wanted to sing it together, I thought, "Whoa, I'm so happy!" I'm glad...
良かったー。
I'm glad too.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
じゃあ、気をつけて帰ってね。
Well then, take care on your way back.
ここから？ここから？
From here? From here?
えっ？
Eh?
じゃあ、じゃあ、ほな、ほな。
Well then, well then, see ya, see ya.
これからも頑張ってください！
Please keep doing your best!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はあと様も頑張ってください！
Haato-sama, please do your best too!
これどうやって帰るの？
How do I go back?
これ、どうやって、どうやって帰るの、これ...
How, how do I go back from here...
あ、あっち？あ、こっち？
Ah, that way? Ah, this way?
あ、あっちとかこっちとかあるんだ、こういうのって。
Ah, so there's "that way" and "this way" in these things.
あ、危ない！
Ah, careful!
はーちゃん、ありがとう！
Haachama, thank you!
頑張ってください！
Do your best!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
はるか遠い遠い昔　巻かれた首輪
A collar put on from a long, long time ago
人が欲しい　人が欲しいと叫ぶ　呪いの首輪
A cursed collar that cries out for people, for people
怒らないで　見捨てないで　どこも行かないで
Don't be mad, don't abandon me, don't go anywhere
（ねえ）
(Hey)
強く締める　吐くまで締める　人がいない　いないと
Tie it tight, tie it until I vomit, if there's no one, no one
いい成績でしょう　ねえ　ねえ　いい子でしょう
I've got good grades, right? Hey, hey, I'm a good child, right?
かわいい子でしょう　ねえ　ねえ
I'm a cute child, right? Hey, hey
いい子でしょう　苦しいねえ
I'm a good child, right? It hurts, doesn't it?
愛して　愛して　愛して　もっともっと
Love me, love me, love me, more and more
愛して　愛して　狂おしいほどに
Love me, love me, so much it makes me go crazy
苦しい　苦しい　呪縛を解いて解いて　ねえ
It hurts, it hurts, untie the curse, untie it, hey
止められない　嗚呼
It can't be stopped, ah
身体　身体　大きくなっても　小さい首輪
My body, my body, even as it grows, the collar stays small
苦しくなる　足りなくなる　人が　人が　足りない
It's painful, it's not enough, people, there aren't enough people
クラスの誰にも負けない　きれいな子でしょう
I'm a prettier child than anyone in my class, right?
（ねえ）
(Hey)
どこよりも　どの何よりも　誰かれ　私を見てよ
More than anywhere, more than anything, everyone, look at me
体育館裏　あなたに告白を
Behind the gymnasium, I confess to you
嘘みたいでしょう　あなたが好きなの　汚いあなたが
It seems like a lie, doesn't it? I love you, even your filthy self
愛して　愛して　愛して
Love me, love me, love me
全部あげる　あなたに　あなたに　全部背負ってもらうよ
I'll give you everything, everything, you'll shoulder it all for me
足りない　あなたが　足りない　離さないよ　嗚呼
It's not enough, you're not enough, I won't let you go, ah
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry
愛して　愛して　愛して　もっともっと
Love me, love me, love me, more and more
愛して　愛して　狂おしいほどに
Love me, love me, so much it makes me go crazy
苦しい　離さない　苦しい　もっともっと　ねえ
It hurts, I won't let go, it hurts, more and more, hey
幸せなの　嗚呼
I'm happy, ah
Yay! Haachama, Shiori, Ina!
Welcome! We're back!
We are back together! It's been so long!
Oh, this is a bear!
I need one too!
Ha-cha-ma-ma!
Oh wow, that's heavy!
Okay, let's fight!
Let's go! Yay!
I like you! I like you! I like you!
It was so nice!
I'm so happy to sing together!
Yeah, and also, Happy Birthday Haachama!
It's a really nice birthday today!
Thank you for letting us celebrate with you!
Thanks for inviting us!
It was so fun!
It's the first time we've been with the... the group!
Yeah, yeah!
And Ina-san and Haachama...
We are Ha-Chi-Ba-Ri-Sa! Ha-Chi-Ba-Ri-Sa!
We made it!
We just jumbled our names together just now!
Let's take a picture!
Everyone take pictures! Ready, go!
Gah! Gah! Gah!
Nice! Yeah, very good screenshots!
That's so cool!
Dangerous, dangerous!
Let's kill the camera! Let's kill them!
The camera?
Say goodbye! Say goodbye to the camera!
Bye bye!
ねぇあたし知ってるよ 君がひとり
Hey, I know. You're all alone.
知ってるの 知ってるよ
I know, I know.
ピコピコ震えてさ 今もただならぬんだわ
Trembling, you're not normal even now.
正直に言っちゃいよ 惚れてるんだし
Just be honest. You're in love.
言っちゃいよ 聞いてんの？
Just say it. Are you listening?
モニタリング
Monitoring
フツフツ恥ずかしい みんな隠しているだけ もー
Simmering with embarrassment, everyone's just hiding it. Geez.
ねぇあたし知ってるよ 君がひとり
Hey, I know. You're all alone,
涙してるの 知ってるよ
shedding tears. I know.
グスングスン凹んでさ 弱音吐いたっていいんじゃない
Sniffling and feeling down, it's okay to whine.
朝が来るまで一緒 覚悟もっと持ってない？
I'm with you until morning. Don't you have more resolve?
だって何度だって受け止めてあげる
Because I'll accept you again and again.
もーが我慢しないで いっぱい出してね
Don't hold back anymore, let it all out.
お願い 君が欲しいの
Please, I want you.
慰めさせて シェイクシェイク愛のサインを頂戴
Let me comfort you. Shake shake, give me a sign of love.
泣いてくれるの？ 枯れちゃうぞ?
Will you cry for me? You'll wither up, you know?
それでも痛いのがいいでしょ
Even so, you like the pain, don't you?
舐め取って飲み干したい ダダダダバ
I want to lick it up and drink it dry. Da-da-da-da-ba.
お願い 君が欲しいの
Please, I want you.
手折って散らして シックシックなんて最高ね
Break it off and scatter it. Feeling 'sick sick' is the best, isn't it?
分けてくれるの？ 君の痛いを出してね
Will you share it with me? Let out your pain.
いいでしょ 掬い取って救いたい ダダダダバ
It's fine, right? I want to scoop it up and save you. Da-da-da-da-ba.
見たい 見たい 見たい 見たい...
I want to see, I want to see, I want to see...
...君の中 見たい
...inside of you. I want to see.
ねぇあたし知ってるよ 君がひとり
Hey, I know. You're all alone,
怖がってるの 知ってるよ
feeling scared. I know.
ズクンズクンハマっちゃう 君を推すことはやめない
Thump-thump, I'm getting hooked. I won't stop supporting you.
ねぇあたし知ってるよ 君がひとり
Hey, I know. You're all alone,
もがいてるの 知ってるよ
struggling. I know.
辛い時は弱いぐらいで丁度いい
When things are tough, being a little weak is just right.
あたしそれでも好きだよ
I'll still love you even then.
お願い 君が欲しいの
Please, I want you.
名前を呼んでよ いつだって愛の感情
Call my name. It's always a feeling of love.
君はひとりじゃない だから歌う
You're not alone. That's why I sing.
ひとりじゃない いいでしょ
You're not alone. It's fine, right?
その不平をお見舞いな ダダダダバ
I'll serve you those complaints. Da-da-da-da-ba.
君がやめる時も あたしそばにいるわ
Even when you quit, I'll be by your side.
いつも見守っているわ さぁもう怖くないのよ
I'm always watching over you. So, don't be afraid anymore.
お願い君が欲しいの
Please, I want you
慰めさせて Shake Shake
Let me comfort you, Shake Shake
愛の才能で
With the talent for love
泣いてくれなきゃ
If you don't cry for me
枯れてしまう
I'll wither away
濡れていたい
I want to be wet
潤っているでしょう？
You're moist, aren't you?
舐めさせて飲み干したい
Let me lick you and drink you dry
タッタッタッパ
Ta ta ta pa
お願い君が欲しいの
Please, I want you
手を出し切って
Reach out your hand
知るのなんて最高ね
It's so great to know
起きてくれなきゃ
If you don't wake up
君の痛い
Your pain
感じていたい
I want to feel it
覗いていたい
I want to peek
掬い取って救いたい
I want to scoop it up and save you
タッタッタッパ
Ta ta ta pa
ねぇ私 知ってるよ
Hey, I know
君の独り占め
Keeping you all to myself
知ってるの 知ってるよ
I know, I know
薬を飲み込んで
Swallow the medicine
最後は私でいいんじゃない？
Isn't it okay if it ends with me?
朝が来るまで
Until morning comes
一緒に遊ぼうよ
Let's play together
何度だって
Over and over again
受け止めてあげる
I'll embrace you
我儘は言わないの
I won't be selfish
タッタッタッパ
Ta ta ta pa
オトノケ
作詞：R-指定 作曲：DJ松永
Otonoke
Lyrics: R-Shitei Composition: DJ Matsunaga
諦めの悪さ やから
Because of my refusal to give up,
あんた等の中 飛ぶなら今 カーニバル
I'm diving into you all now, it's a carnival.
クワバラ クワバラ クワバラ
Kuwabara kuwabara kuwabara
目にも留まらぬ速さ
With a speed too fast for the eye to catch.
たまらん たまらん さから
It's irresistible, irresistible, so...
お一つも我儘
not even a single selfish request.
解けぬ謎邪魔
Unsolved mysteries are a nuisance,
俺はもう一人の貴方
I am your other self.
猿ちゃん 恋ちゃん ワサカ
Saru-chan, Koi-chan, wasaka,
闇の国へ渡ら
crossing over to the land of darkness.
ガキたちの中 4時44分まで 踊ろよ
Let's dance among the brats until 4:44 AM.
4時4分4秒が 踏み出す バカバカ
At 4:04:04, stepping out, stupidly stupid.
呼ぶ声がしたなら
If you hear a voice calling,
お疲れ様よ
good work.
晴れた 晴れた 晴れた 晴れた
It cleared up, cleared up, cleared up, cleared up.
消して 吐き出した 先で 霧は晴れた
Beyond the point where I breathed it out, the mist cleared.
凸と凹が 上手く噛み合ったら
If the convex and concave fit together perfectly,
痛みがクスになったら
if the pain turns into a drug,
心 体 頭 皆消えていく
heart, body, and head, everything fades away.
中々 背中に今 羽が生えたならば
Somewhat, if wings grew on my back now,
暗闇から サラバ
farewell to the darkness.
飛び立っていく 体
My body takes flight.
心 体 頭 懐かしい 暖かさ
Heart, body, head, a nostalgic warmth.
足元に今 花が咲いたならば
If flowers bloomed at my feet now,
暗闇から サラバ
farewell to the darkness.
飛び立っていく 体
My body takes flight.
何度だって生きる お前や君の中
Living over and over within you and yourself.
瞼の裏 闇の中
Behind the eyelids, in the darkness.
胸の奥に 鳴り続ける メロディ
The melody that keeps ringing deep in my chest,
リズムに
to the rhythm.
今日も最高に 変わらずの 真ん中
Today too, at the very center, unchanging.
積み上げていく ドップドップ
Stacking it up, drop drop.
鬼とチャンバラで リリカルジャストマッサカー
Sword fighting with demons, lyrical just massacre.
歌おう 大海原 鼻歌で シャララ
Let's sing to the great ocean, humming sha-la-la.
払いたいなら もっと まだまだ さぁさぁ
If you want to cast it away, more, still more, come on.
誰が開いたか パンドラ 後は何があっても 知らんがな
Who opened Pandora's box? Whatever happens next, I don't care.
何百年 待ったか 超久しぶりのシャバだ
How many hundreds of years have I waited? It's been so long since I've been out.
餓鬼は若葉 丸ごと 食ってやろうか バカが
The brat is like a young leaf, shall I eat you whole? You idiot.
今 確かに 目が合ったな こういう事かよ シャーマン
Now, our eyes definitely met. So this is how it is, shaman.
晴れた 晴れた 晴れた 晴れた
It cleared up, cleared up, cleared up, cleared up.
眠り飽きた 先で 君が待ってた
Past the point of being tired of sleeping, you were waiting.
盾と矛が 肩を抱き合ったら
If the shield and spear embraced each other,
怒りが 消え去ったら
if the anger vanished,
心 体 頭 皆消えていく
heart, body, and head, everything fades away.
中々 背中に今 羽が生えたならば
Somewhat, if wings grew on my back now,
暗闇から サラバ
farewell to the darkness.
飛び立っていく 体
My body takes flight.
心 体 頭 懐かしい 暖かさ
Heart, body, head, a nostalgic warmth.
足元に今 花が咲いたならば
If flowers bloomed at my feet now,
暗闇から サラバ
farewell to the darkness.
飛び立っていく 体
My body takes flight.
何度だって生きる お前や君の中
Living over and over within you and yourself.
瞼の裏 闇の中
Behind the eyelids, in the darkness.
胸の奥に 鳴り続ける メロディ
The melody that keeps ringing deep in my chest,
リズムに
to the rhythm.
ちゃま...
Chama...
はぁ...
Haa...
ちゃま...
Chama...
大切な...
Precious...
家族...
Family...
爆誕ライブの途中ですが
We're in the middle of my birthday live, but
ここからはちょっと外にくり出して
from here, I'm going to step outside for a bit
ロケをしていこうと思います
and do a location shoot.
ここはですね...
This place is...
私が...
where I...
私が前から会いたかった方の
I'm at the home of someone...
ご自宅ということなんですが
...I've wanted to meet for a long time.
何やらとんでもない雰囲気が漂ってます
There's quite an ominous atmosphere here.
この階段の先に…
Beyond these stairs...
オカルト界隈でも有名な
...is a curse object collector...
呪物コレクターの方がいるはずなので
...who's famous in the occult world.
早速、突撃してみたいと思います
I'm going to head in and say hello right away!
行きましょう
Let's go!
ドキドキ
*Heart Pounding*
結構…
Wow...
階段の段差が…
...these stairs are steep.
うおぉぉ
Whoa...
めっちゃ暗い
It's so dark.
一番奥のお部屋のはずなので
It should be the room at the very back,
先に進んで行きましょう
so let's keep going.
なんかスゴイ…
This is intense...
異質ですね
It feels surreal.
この部屋なんですね
This must be the room.
表札もないですが
There's no nameplate,
一応ノックしてみますか？
but should I try knocking anyway?
トントン
*Knock Knock*
あれ… ここであってますかね？
Huh... is this the right place?
もう一度ノックしてみますか
Let me try knocking one more time.
はい
Yes?
声が…
A voice!
あ…
Ah...
どうも
Hello.
あ、どうも
Oh, hello.
あの、田中さんですか？
Um, are you Mr. Tanaka?
はい
Yes.
ホロライブ1期生の赤井はあとと申します
I'm Akai Haato from Hololive's 1st Generation.
インタビュー撮影に来たんですが
I'm here for an interview shoot.
もし良かったら撮影… 大丈夫ですか？
If it's alright, could we film here?
大丈夫ですよ
That's fine.
ホントですか！？
Really!?
ありがとうございます
Thank you so much!
そういう約束してましたっけ？ すいません
Wait, did we have an appointment? I'm sorry.
忘れてました？
Did you forget?
ちょっと忘れてましたね
I did forget, actually.
あ…
Oh...
すでになんか、色々見えてますけども
I can already see all sorts of things...
入ってもいいですか？
Can I come in?
はい、どうぞ
Yes, please.
お邪魔します
Excuse me.
失礼します
Coming in.
これ全部、呪物なんですか？
Are all of these cursed objects?
そうなんですよね
That's right.
呪物というか、まぁ…
Well, cursed objects, or...
呪われた…
...cursed...
あ、呪われた！
Oh, cursed!
呪われちゃってるんだ…
So they're actually cursed.
田中さんは大丈夫なんですか？
Are you doing okay, Mr. Tanaka?
いや、でもずっとしんどいですよ
No, it's actually exhausting all the time.
えぇ！？
What!?
全部ちゃんと呪われてる…
So every single one is properly cursed...
そうですね、中にはまぁ、あの…
Yes. Though among them...
良いものもありますけど
...there are some good ones too.
そうなんですね
I see.
呪いにも種類があるんですか？
So there are different types of curses?
ありますね
There are.
ちなみに、今配信を見てる人たちのために
By the way, for the people watching this stream,
田中さんがどんな方なのか、自己紹介してもらってもよろしいですか？
could you please introduce yourself?
呪物コレクター、田中俊行です。よろしくお願いします。
I'm Tanaka Toshiyuki, a curse object collector. Nice to meet you.
よろしくお願いします
Nice to meet you too.
仕事は怪談師なんですよ
My profession is telling ghost stories.
怖い話ですね
Scary stories.
そうなんだ！
Oh, I see!
趣味、ライフワークで
As a hobby and my life's work,
趣味なんだ…
It's a hobby...
呪われたものを集めてる
I collect cursed objects.
今、田中さんが立ってる奥の部屋にも呪物があるんですか？
Does that room behind you also have cursed objects in it?
元々こっちだけが呪物部屋だったんですけど
Originally, only this room was the curse object room,
あ、そうなんですね
Oh, really?
量が入り切らなくなって
but I ran out of space,
奥にも…
so the back room too...
入れたりするんですか？
Can we go in there?
奥入れますけど
You can go in, but...
奥は比較的
...the ones in the back are mostly...
僕が個人的に契約してる呪物が多いんで
...cursed objects I've personally contracted with.
へぇ〜！
Whoa!
入らない方がいい
It's better not to enter.
危ない！
It's dangerous!
入ったら危ない
It's dangerous if you go in.
あんまし多分、呪物が嫌がると思います
I think the objects there wouldn't like it.
あ〜、そんな感じなんだ
Ah, I see how it is.
最初にここ入って
Coming in here,
1番気になったのが
the thing that caught my eye first...
赤いお面の横にある、白いお面で
...was that white mask next to the red one.
はいはい
Yes, that one.
あれはどういう呪物なんですか？
What kind of cursed object is that?
あれは「呪いの面」
That is the 'Mask of Curses'.
って言われてて
That's what it's called.
呪いの面…
The Mask of Curses...
こう、つけたら
If you wear it,
不幸が訪れるって言われてるんですよ
it's said that misfortune will visit you.
あ、え！？
Oh, what!?
実際に、そうやって不幸が起こっちゃった人もいる？
Are there people who actually experienced misfortune?
います
There are.
京都の蓮久寺っていうお寺
At a temple in Kyoto called Renkyu-ji,
そこに三木大雲さんという和尚がいるんですよ
there's a monk named Miki Daiun.
うんうん
Uh-huh.
三木大雲さんから預かったもので
It's something I was entrusted with by him.
へぇ〜
Wow.
たぶんこれ[ピー]だと思いますけど
This will probably be [beeped out], but...
[ピー]と[ピー]がつけたっていうんですよ
[Beep] and [Beep] wore it.
え、つけたの！？
What, they wore it!?
え、なんでつけちゃったんですか？
Why on earth did they wear it?
そういう番組があったっていうんですよ
They were on a certain TV program.
試しにつけちゃえみたいなノリで？
Just like, 'Hey, let's try it on'?
がっつり呪われちゃいましたね
They got thoroughly cursed.
えぇー
No way...
ちゃんと呪われてる…
So it's really cursed...
基本
Basically,
お祓いが済んでない
...objects that haven't been exorcised...
えっ、もの、が
...um, things...
ここでは普通です
...are the norm here.
だから僕も、そういう呪物受け取る時に
So when I receive these cursed objects,
人を呪ったものとかありますけど
even the ones used to curse people,
「お祓いはやめてくれ」って言います
I tell them, 'Please don't exorcise it'.
(笑い)
(Laughter)
珍しいｗ
That's unusual (lol).
意味がなくなるので
Because otherwise, it's pointless.
え、じゃあ、田中さんおすすめの呪物はありますか？
Well then, do you have any recommended cursed objects?
あります、あります
I do, I do.
おおぉ！
Ooh!
じゃあちょっと持ってきますわ
I'll go get one then.
持ってきてくれるんですね！
You're getting it for us!
お願いしま〜す！
Please do!
あ、お人形さんだ！
Oh, it's a doll!
お人形さん持ってきてくれた
He brought out a doll.
あ、奥の部屋…
Oh, from the back room...
奥の部屋、あれですよね、契約の部屋ですけど
That's the 'Contract Room', right?
大丈夫なんですか…？
Is it really okay...?
危険な…
The dangerous...
危険なって
Dangerous, you say.
出せっていうから
Because she said she wanted to come out.
えー！ちょっと待って
Ehh! Wait a second.
あ、でも可愛い
Oh, but she's cute.
可愛い、なんか
She looks cute.
可愛くない？パジャマ着てるし
Isn't she? She's wearing pajamas.
ジェラピケ着てるんですか？
Is that Gelato Pique?
え、ジェラピケじゃない、あ、やっぱジェラピケなんだ！
Wait, is it? Oh, it really is Gelato Pique!
なんでお気に入りなんですか？
Why is she your favorite?
こう、呪物を集める…
Well, when collecting these objects...
呪物を集めるきっかけになった人形...
The doll that started my cursed object collection...
どういうきっかけで？
How did it start?
元々怪談ライブとかやってたらお客さんが...
I used to do ghost story live events...
あの、持ってくんですよね、相談。
...and customers would bring them for consultation.
お祓いとかも出来ると思われてて。
They thought I could perform exorcisms too.
ちなみにお名前はなんて？
By the way, what is its name?
チャーミーって。
It's Charmy.
あ、チャーミーさん。
Ah, Charmy-san.
関西の、ある介護施設にいたんですよ。
She was in a nursing home in Kansai.
へぇ〜そうなんですね。
Oh, I see.
で、誰が持ってきたかスタッフの人もわからない。
Even the staff didn't know who brought her.
特定の利用者の人が何故か可愛がるんですよ。
Specific residents would adore her for some reason.
え、あ、へぇ。
Oh, wow.
可愛がると三日以内に死ぬんです。
If they adored her, they'd die within three days.
えっ...
What...
それが5人続いたので。
That happened to five people in a row.
5人も続いたんですね...
Five people in a row...
なので一度地下の倉庫に隠した...
So she was hidden in the basement warehouse...
あ、隠されちゃったんだ。
Oh, she was hidden away.
次の日には出てきてた。
But she was back the next day.
ちゃんと脱出してるｗ
She escaped properly lol.
スタッフの人が僕のこと知ってて...
The staff knew about me...
田中さんに預けようということで持ってきてくれたんです。
...and brought her to me for safekeeping.
あ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
で、バタバタしてたんで僕そのまま...
I was busy, so I just...
中身見ずに家に帰った。
...went home without looking inside.
家に帰ったら部屋の明かりが...
When I got home, the room lights...
激しく明滅する。
...started flickering violently.
PC立ち上げてメールの返信しようと思っても...
I tried to reply to emails on my PC, but...
音声認識ソフトが立ち上がって他のアプリが開けない。
Speech recognition software opened and blocked other apps.
で、袋を開けたらこの子が出てきた。
So I opened the bag, and she came out.
その瞬間に現象が一気に止んだ。
At that moment, the phenomena stopped instantly.
じゃあもう早く出してくれっていうやつだったんですかね。
So it was like a 'get me out of here' message.
でもめっちゃ可愛い服まで着せて可愛がってますけどｗ
But you're adoring her with such cute clothes lol.
僕はだから、この場では仲良いフリしてますけど。
So, I'm just pretending to be friendly here.
全然可愛がってない？
You don't adore her at all?
可愛がってないというか、敬ってます。
It's not that I adore her; I revere her.
そこからものに霊的なものとか魂みたいなものが...
That's when I felt that spiritual things or souls...
宿るんじゃないかなって。
...could dwell in objects.
現象が起きた時は怖くなかった？
Weren't you scared when it happened?
いや、めちゃくちゃ怖いです。
No, I was terrified.
ちゃんと怖かったんだ！
So you were actually scared!
めちゃくちゃ怖いです。
I'm extremely scared.
次ちょっと最近送られてきたものがあって...
Next, there's something that was sent recently...
それ見てほしいんですけど。
I want you to see it.
これなんですよ。
It's this.
大量の●●●●人形。
A large number of ●●●● dolls.
すごいね...あの、執着が。
Wow... such obsession.
「こんなにする？」っていうくらい。
To the point where you'd say, 'This much?'
これは遊びじゃなくて...
This isn't play...
姉妹の妹が姉を呪ってた。
The younger sister was cursing the older sister.
ずーっと何年も。
Constantly, for years.
「死ね死ね死ね」と思ってずっとこれを。
Thinking 'Die die die' while doing this.
実際この姉妹がどうなったかというと...
As for what happened to the sisters...
姉の方が精神病院に入院したんですよ。
The older sister was hospitalized in a mental ward.
で結局、妹も入院して二人とも入院してるんです。
In the end, the younger sister was also hospitalized.
あれとかないですか？はあとさんは。
Do you have anything like that, Haato-san?
呪いたい相手とかいないんですか？
Anyone you want to curse?
私が呪いたい相手？いないですね。
Someone I want to curse? No one.
呪っちゃったら自分にも対価がくるから。
If I curse someone, I have to pay the price too.
「返ってくる」っていうのはありますね。
The 'karma' thing is real.
返ってくるんだったら嫌です。
I don't want it if it comes back to me.
そしたらクイックに呪えるやつはありますよ。
Well, there's one that can curse quickly.
呪い教えてくれるんだｗ
You're teaching me curses lol.
これとかは呪ったりするんですか？
Do you use this to curse people?
僕、呪ったりしますから。
I do curse people sometimes.
誰呪うんですか？ｗ
Who do you curse? lol
アンチをずっと呪ってます。
I'm always cursing my haters.
これは西アフリカの呪術師が作ったんですけど。
This was made by a sorcerer in West Africa.
どういう効果があるかって言ったら...
As for what effect it has...
これ、刺せるようになってるんですよね。
It's designed to be pierced.
ここに呪いたい相手の名前を言えと。
You say the target's name into it.
名前だけでいいんだ。デスノートみたいな。
Just the name? Like a Death Note.
それでこう、刺すと。
And then you pierce it.
そいつも不幸になるし、気持ちもすっきりする。
They'll be miserable, and you'll feel better.
部屋の中で一番呪力が強い呪物ってあるんですか？
Is there a cursed object with the strongest power?
こんだけ集めてると、わからない場合があるんですが。
With this many, it's hard to tell sometimes.
最近、誰からもらったのかまったくわからへん...
Recently, there's a doll I have no idea who sent it...
身に覚えがないぞっていう人形があるんですよ。
I have absolutely no memory of acquiring it.
え、見たいです。ぜひお願いします。
Oh, I want to see it! Please.
すごい気持ち悪い人形なんですよｗ
It's a really creepy doll lol.
これなんですけどね。
This is it.
ｗｗｗ あれｗ
Lol, what?!
あれ、タランちゃま...？ｗ
Is that... Taran-chama...? lol
どういう人が作ったんですかね...
I wonder what kind of person made this...
えっ、これ、これ、これ、これ...
Wait, this, this, this, this...
これ私のお姉ちゃんが作ったやつ... これ
This is something my sister made... this one.
はあとさんのお姉ちゃんが作ったんですか...
Your sister made it, Haato-san...?
私のお姉ちゃんが作った...
My sister made it...
クモのね...
The spider one...
あ、これがね
Ah, this one.
そうそうそう。体もクモになってるんですよ
Right, right. The body is a spider too.
けっこうセンスありますよね
She has quite good taste, doesn't she?
お、すごいですよねこれ
Oh, it's amazing, isn't it?
ぜひ置いておいてください
Please keep it here.
あ、いいんですか？
Oh, is that okay?
じゃあ置いておこうかな...
I'll leave it here then...
これね、呪いはない気もするけど...
I don't think there's a curse, but...
すごい馴染んでるw
It fits in really well lol
（日くが）なんもない人形も、こういう場所に置いておけば...
Even a plain doll, if you put it in a place like this...
え、大丈夫ですか？私のお姉ちゃんが作ったんですけど
Wait, is it okay? My sister made it, though.
お姉ちゃん呪われちゃったりとかしません？
Will my sister get cursed or something?
お姉ちゃん作ってるだけなんで
She only made it, so...
あ、そっか。そっか。作った人... わ、私...？
Oh, right. Right. The person who made it? Wait, me...?
でもね... うん... はい
But... yes...
これホンマに... ちょっと嫌なこと言いますけど
Honestly... I'm going to say something a bit unpleasant.
えっ、なんですか？あの...
Wait, what is it? Umm...
さっきから、はあとさんの後ろに、ずっと誰か居ますよね？
For a while now, there's been someone behind you, Haato-san.
あんまし言いたくなかったんですけど、ずっと誰か憑いてきてますよ
I didn't really want to say it, but someone has been following you the whole time.
え？
Eh?
待ったをかけた ちょっと考えた バカな女 まんまとかった
I put a stop to it, thought for a bit. Stupid woman, easily caught.
だからどした 自ら望んだと言ってんじゃん
So what? I'm telling you it was my own wish.
待ったをかけた ちょっと考えた
I put a stop to it, thought for a bit.
少々ちょっと考えた
A little bit, thought for a bit.
ほら だからどした お望み通りの結末です
Look, so what? It's the ending you wished for.
なんで なんで なんで なんで なんで なんでなの どうしたつもり
Why, why, why, why, why, why? What's the plan?
なんで なんで なんで なんで なんで なんだそんなもんか
Why, why, why, why, why? Is that all?
まあそういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうだ 違いない
Well, is that how it is? That's how it is. Surely it is. No doubt about it.
まあそういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうだ 絶対に
Well, is that how it is? That's how it is. Surely it is. Absolutely.
まあそういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうだ 違いない
Well, is that how it is? That's how it is. Surely it is. No doubt about it.
まあそういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうだ 違いないの
違いないよ 絶対
No doubt about it, absolutely.
待ったをかけた ちょっと躊躇った 確かに躊躇った
I put a stop to it, hesitated a bit. I certainly hesitated.
なんだかなあ なんだかなあ こういうことではない
Somehow, somehow, this isn't it.
待ったをかけた ちょっと躊躇った なんだなんだなんだあなた
I put a stop to it, hesitated a bit. What, what, what are you?
だから だから こんなことは望んでないから
So, so, because I didn't wish for something like this.
なんで なんで なんで なんで なんで なんでなの
Why, why, why, why, why, why?
どうしたつもり なんで なんで なんで なんで なんで
What's the plan? Why, why, why, why, why?
黙って私に従って
Shut up and obey me.
従え 従え 従え 君に一切の拒否権ないよ
Obey, obey, obey. You have no right to refuse at all.
黙って従って
Shut up and obey.
黙って私に従って
Shut up and obey me.
従え 従え 従え
Obey, obey, obey.
お願い お願い お願い お願いよ
Please, please, please, I beg you.
黙って私に従って
Shut up and obey me.
従え 従え 従え
Obey, obey, obey.
従え 従えって言ってんの
I'm telling you to obey!
黙って私に従って
Shut up and obey me.
従え 従え 従え お願い...
Obey, obey, obey, please...
ということで、サロメちゃんに来てもらったよ！
So, we have Salome-chan here!
一、十、百、千、満点サロメ！
One, ten, hundred, thousand, Hyakumantenbara Salome!
皆様方を100万点満点の笑顔にさせて頂きますわ！
I'll make everyone have a 1,000,000-point smile!
今はまだ一般人、いつかお嬢様になりたい、そして今日は、はあと様をお祝いしに来ました！
Right now I'm just an ordinary person, but I want to become a lady someday! And today, I came to celebrate Haato-sama!
100万点満原サロメでございますわ！はあと様！
I am Hyakumantenbara Salome! Haato-sama!
サロメちゃーん！来てくれてありがとう！
Salome-chan! Thank you for coming!
「下屑」一緒に歌えてすごく嬉しい！
I'm so happy we could sing 'Gesō' together!
歌ってみたも本当に最高でした！
The cover version was also absolutely amazing!
普段お上品なサロメちゃんのヤンデレ感がたまりませんでした！
The yandere vibe from the usually elegant Salome-chan was irresistible!
歌声も喋り方も性格も、好きです！
Your voice, the way you talk, and your personality... I love it all!
はあと様、本当にありがとうございます！
Haato-sama, thank you so much!
こちらこそ！
Likewise!
なんかこうして、縁が繋がって、
I'm so glad that our connection has led us here,
こうして今、一緒に歌を歌えたのがすごく嬉しいですわ！
and that we're able to sing together like this now!
もうすごい、わたくしもはあと様のこと全部可愛いと思ってるし、本当に...
I think everything about you is cute, Haato-sama! Truly...
可愛い！
So cute!
おめでとう。今日は本当にありがとうございました、はあと様！
Congratulations. Thank you so much for today, Haato-sama!
こちらこそありがとう！
Thank you as well!
さようなら、またねー！
Goodbye, see you again!
厄介なしのサタデー主様 お隣に座って せーの
Trouble-free Saturday, Master. Sit next to me, and... one, two...
萌え萌え萌え萌え
Moe moe moe moe.
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ ねえ教えて
Who would be happy with this? Hey, tell me.
笑顔でアップ・プ
With a smile, Up-pu-pu
愛想忘れてご苦労様
Thanks for your hard work, forgetting your manners
私とあなたでせーの、ラブ・ラブ・ラブ・ラブ
You and me together, one-two—love, love, love, love
こんなので誰が喜ぶのさ
Who would be happy with something like this?
ねえ教えて笑顔でアップ・プー
Hey, tell me, with a smile, Up-pu-puu
ひらり はらり 女の子
Fluttering, fluttering girl
ふわり ふわり 言葉の嘘
Softly, softly, a lie of words
それってつまり幼な子
That means, in other words, a child
感情的リアル 笑顔でアップ・プ
Emotional reality, with a smile, Up-pu-pu
人は見かけによらぬもの
People aren't always what they seem
嘘は嘘だとなぜ見抜けない
Why can't you see a lie for what it is?
仕方がなさそでその皮
It can't be helped, that skin of yours
鳥肌 鮫肌 Under
Goosebumps, sharkskin, Under
間違ったご指名を頂きます
I'll take your mistaken nomination
私とあなたでせーの、ラブ・ラブ・ラブ・ラブ
You and me together, one-two—love, love, love, love
これはど派手にご苦労様
This is quite flashily done, thanks for the work
遊びましょう笑顔でアップ・プ
Let's play, with a smile, Up-pu-pu
ひらり はらり ここはどこ
Fluttering, fluttering, where am I?
ふわり ふわり 外れショー
Softly, softly, an off-target show
それってつまり幼な子
That means, in other words, a child
感情的リアル 笑顔でアップ・プー
Emotional reality, with a smile, Up-pu-puu
歌い出す 秘密の枷
Start to sing, the secret shackles
終わることのないこの世界
This world that never ends
悲しい子供は
The sad children...
虚しい子供は 眠らせて
...the hollow children, let them sleep.
おままごと 遊びましょう笑顔でアップ・プ
Playing house, let's play, with a smile, Up-pu-pu
ひらり はらり 女の子
Fluttering, fluttering girl
ふわり ふわり 言葉の嘘
Softly, softly, a lie of words
それってつまり幼な子
That means, in other words, a child
感情的リアル 笑顔でアップ・プ
Emotional reality, with a smile, Up-pu-pu
遊びましょう笑顔でアップ・プ
Let's play, with a smile, Up-pu-pu
アップ・プ
Up-pu-pu
星街すいせーい！
Hoshimachi Suisei!
わー！
Waa!
誕生日おめでとー！
Happy birthday!
来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming!
おいすー！なんとね、2021年の4年ぶりにデュエットしました！
Oissu! Believe it or not, we performed a duet for the first time in 4 years, since 2021!
4年！
4 years!
4年ぶり。チューリングラブ歌ったの覚えてる？
It's been 4 years. Do you remember when we sang Turing Love?
覚えてるよー！4年前に！
I remember! 4 years ago!
そうそうそう。あの時は若かったねー。
Right, right. We were so young back then.
え、今はなんか違う？若くない？
Wait, is it different now? Are we not young anymore?
あ、今はでもクールになったもんね、我々。今日クール可愛かったもんね。
Ah, well, we've become cool now. We were cool and cute today, weren't we?
確かにね。いつものチューリングラブこんなことしたもんね。
True. We used to do things like this for Turing Love.
そう！あとなんかおたけびとかしたもんね。
Yeah! And we used to shout too.
こんなことしてたのに。チューリングラブ、自由だったけど。
We used to do all that. Turing Love was so free.
だいぶクールになりましたよ。
We've become quite cool.
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
ちょっと... 自由すぎるだろ！
Wait... you're being too free!
どうしたの？
What happened?
わかんないよー。写真とか...
I don't know. How about some photos...
そうね、あの今日歌った『燃えちゃっかファイア』ね、歌ってみたも出してるのでぜひ見てください。
Right, the 'Moe Chaka Fire' we sang today—I've released a cover of it, so please check it out.
え、なんでこの曲にしてくれたんですか？
Why did you choose this song?
え、これ歌いたかった！やっぱ歌ってみたも出したし、生誕でも一緒に歌いたいなと思って選びました！
I really wanted to sing it! Since I released the cover, I thought I'd like to sing it with you for my birthday too!
おー！なんか意外な選曲だった、個人的には。
Oh! It was an unexpected choice, personally.
え、本当に？え、なんか今回ホラーライブがテーマなんだけど。
Really? Well, the theme this time is 'Horror Live'...
ホラー！？そんなコンセプトのライブ見たことない！
Horror!? I've never seen a live show with that concept!
いや、なんかちょっと合うかなと思って選びました。
No, I just thought it might fit a bit.
あーなるほどね、ちょっとね、落ち着いてね。
Ah, I see. Calm down a bit.
なんか一緒に写真とか撮る？
Want to take some photos together?
撮る！撮る！てかすごいマジで、ライブステージ！ねー、めっちゃ可愛い！
Let's! Seriously, this live stage is amazing! It's so cute!
え、なんかいいポーズ、やりたいポーズとかある？
Is there any pose you want to do?
え、まず普通に。まず普通に、イエーイ！
First, just a normal one. Normal, yay!
パシャ。え、可愛い！パシャパシャ。
Snap. Oh, cute! Snap snap.
ぎゅーってことでしょ。
Let's do a hug.
あとあと、ハート。ハート、ハートしとく？
And, a heart. Should we do a heart?
できてる？
Are we doing it right?
いい感じ！いい感じ！よっし。
Looking good! Looking good! Alright.
ひょきひょき。
Hyoki hyoki.
あとは、え、あと何だろう？なんかデカくなって。あ、これこれこれ。これこれこれ。
Next... what else? Something big. Ah, this, this, this!
やだー！うわぁー！
Nooo! Waaaa!
って感じでね。
Like that.
あれは4年前にもさ、撮ったさ、なんかちょっと座ってエモめみたいな。
Let's do that one we took 4 years ago, where we sat down and looked 'emo'.
あ！こっちじゃない。こっちじゃない、みんなの方向いてね。
Ah! Not this way. This way, facing everyone.
あ、いい！いいじゃん！4年前もこれで撮ったんだよ。
Ah, nice! That's it! We took one like this 4 years ago too.
イエーイ！みんな見てるー！？
Yay! Everyone, are you watching!?
イエーイ！久しぶりのはちゃま。
Yay! It's been a while, Haachama.
衣装も変わって。イエーイ！本当だね、二人とも衣装変わった。
Our outfits have changed too. Yeah! We both have different outfits now.
え、めっちゃ可愛い、その衣装。
Oh, that outfit is so cute.
え、星街もめっちゃ可愛い。あ、これはでも、あしふぇち向けな衣装だね、衣装。
Hoshimachi, yours is really cute too. Ah, but this one is definitely for the leg-fetishists.
いや、そっちでしょ！だいじょぶ？
No, that's you! You okay?
これ、アートは結構隠してるけど...
Haato covers it up quite a bit, but...
...この足よ！
...look at these legs!
違う、隠してるのが逆にいいんだって。
No, hiding it is actually better.
あ、そういうこと？チラ見えのね。
Oh, I see? A peek-a-boo thing.
わかってんじゃん。
You get it.
そうだよね。
Right.
やばい、絵面やばい！
This is crazy, the shot is crazy!
だいぶの絵面じゃなかった今。
Wasn't that quite a shot just now?
絶対領域がね。
The absolute territory, right.
どう？なんかセクシーポーズとかしなくて大丈夫？
How about it? Is it okay if we don't do a sexy pose or something?
セクシーポーズ？したいの？
A sexy pose? You want to do one?
大丈夫かな。いや、大丈夫です！
Is it okay? No, I'm good!
おめでとう誕生日！
Happy birthday!
あー、ありがとー！
Ah, thank you!
またね、なんか一緒に歌って踊りたい。
I want to sing and dance together again sometime.
うん。踊ろう、ぜひ。
Yeah. Let's dance, definitely.
ぜひとも。また次も踊りましょー！
By all means. Let's dance next time too!
じゃあ、バイバーイ！
Well then, bye-bye!
あ、バイバーイ！頑張ってね！
Ah, bye-bye! Good luck!
ありがとう！バイバイ！
Thank you! Bye-bye!
正しくなれない
Tadashiku Narenai
正しくなれない 霧がどこをみた
I can't be right, where did the fog look?
片っ端から 確かめたくて
I want to check everything one by one
考え続けたい 偽りで出会った
I want to keep thinking, we met with lies
僕らは何ひとつも 奪われてないから
Because not a single thing has been taken from us
作詞・作曲：ACAね
Lyrics/Composition: ACAne
僕ら育ってくみたい 愛されるみたい
It seems like we're growing, it seems like we're being loved
暖かな波を読む
Reading the warm waves
代わり映えしない今を選ぶ
Choosing the unchanging present
澄んだ朝色 訪ねる声で
With a clear morning color, with a visiting voice
何度でも 僕ら嘘つきだね
Time and time again, we're liars, aren't we?
両想いだね
We're in love with each other
枯れ果てるまで 泣き笑い
Crying and laughing until we're withered and exhausted
今日を受け入れてく
Accepting today
喜びあった日々を 忘れ出しはしないけど
I won't start forgetting the days we shared joy, but
知らない方が幸せだって 知れば
If I know that not knowing would have been happier
知り得るほど
The more I get to know...
正しくなれない 霧がどこをみた
I can't be right, where did the fog look?
片っ端から 確かめたくて
I want to check everything one by one
考え続けたい 偽りで出会った
I want to keep thinking, we met with lies
僕らは何ひとつも 奪われてないから
Because not a single thing has been taken from us
今心閉ざさないように 虎視眈々と
So that I don't close my heart now, vigilantly
これを続けよう 枯れ木に笑顔だけ
Let's continue this, just a smile on a dead tree
君の肉体欲しい 全て
I want your body, everything
無駄に泣かせないよ
I won't let you cry in vain
ねぇ 知り得るほど幸せだって
Hey, the more I get to know, I'm happy...
辿り着いてもいい？
Is it okay if I reach that point?
君だけが見る 夕焼け風鏡
The sunset-colored mirror that only you look at
僕でもいつか分かる日まで
Until the day even I understand
考え続けたい 偽りで出会った
I want to keep thinking, we met with lies
重なる枝分かれ 導かれ
Overlapping branches, being guided
大したもんじゃない 無駄なもんじゃない
It's not a big deal, it's not a waste
幸せの理を 甘いにしていくように
As if making the logic of happiness something sweet
ずっと もうずっと
Forever, already forever
茶化されようが 折れない素直花
Even if made fun of, the honest flower that doesn't break
可能性が 見逃せるならば
If the possibilities can be overlooked...
可能性を 諦められないから
Because I can't give up on the possibilities
まだ
Still...
正しくなれない 霧がどこをみた
I can't be right, where did the fog look?
片っ端から 確かめたくて
I want to check everything one by one
考え続けたい 偽りで出会った
I want to keep thinking, we met with lies
僕らは何ひとつも
We are, not a single thing...
すべて嫌われても
Even if we are hated by everything
奪われてないから
Because nothing has been taken from us
はあとちゃん、大好きだよ！チュッ
Haato-chan, I love you! *mwah*
はあちゃま、はあちゃま、
Haachama, Haachama,
私も大好き。
I love you too.
今までごめん。
Sorry for everything until now.
ごめんなさい。
I'm sorry.
いなくなって寂しかったよ。
I was lonely when you were gone.
いつもそばにいるって言ったじゃん。
I told you I'd always be by your side.
ずっと待ってたよ。
I've been waiting for you all this time.
おー！はーちゃま...
Oh! Haachama...
はーちゃまっちゃまー！はーちゃまだよ！
Haachamachama! It's Haachama!
こうやって対話するのは初めてだよね。
This is the first time we've spoken like this, right?
さっき歌ってた感触、最高だったよ！
The feel of singing just now was the best!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
なんか大人っぽくなったね！
You've become quite mature!
実は最近、旅をすることが増えまして...
Actually, I've been traveling more lately...
...そこで新しい自分を見つけて、
...and I found a new side of myself there,
ちょっぴり大人っぽい曲にチャレンジしてみました。
so I tried challenging a slightly more mature song.
ほおー。特に好きな歌詞とかはある？
Oho. Are there any lyrics in particular you like?
はい。『もう一度 もう一度と
Yes. There's a lyric that goes,
何度思ったでしょう』という歌詞がありまして...
'I wonder how many times I thought, "Once more, once more"'...
出会った景色や人の温もりを思いながら、
While thinking of the scenery and people's warmth,
すごく感情移入しました。
I really empathized with it.
ほおー、そうなんだ！
Oho, is that so!
今日リリース予定なので、みんなもたくさん聴いてね！
It's out today, so everyone, please listen to it a lot!
ぜひぜひ！
Please do!
デュエットで『正しくなれない』歌ったよ。
We sang 'Cannot Be Right' as a duet.
どうだった？
How was it?
今までの記憶とか葛藤を振り返りながらで、
Reflecting on my past memories and struggles,
すごく心に沁みましたね。
it really touched my heart.
本当だよー！
Exactly!
はあーちゃんはさ、ずっと塞ぎ込んで、
Ha-chan, you were always moping around,
全然はーちゃまのこと見向きもしないんだもん！
you wouldn't even look at Haachama!
そんなことないけど、ごめんね。
That's not true, but I'm sorry.
でもお互い知り合って、分かり合えたから、
But I'm glad we got to know and
良かったなって思うよ。
understand each other now.
おー、ならいっか！
Oh, well that's fine then!
そんな二人の家族写真を今回は撮ってもらいました！
We had a family photo taken of us this time!
二人の仲良しの証！
A proof of our close relationship!
はい。B2タペストリーになっております！
Yes. It's available as a B2 tapestry!
おしゃれだ！
It's so stylish!
はあちゃまいくよ。
Haachama, let's go.
あ、うん。
Ah, okay.
せーの！
One, two...!
グッズ！グッズ！ゲットしてください！
Merch! Merch! Please get it!
お人形
作詞・作曲・編曲：白石誠美
The Doll
Lyrics, Music, Arrangement: Narumi Shiraishi
ねえ見て お気に入りの
Hey, look at my favorite,
世界に一つの お人形さん
one-of-a-kind doll in the world
顔も性格も 違ったけど
Our faces and personalities were different,
ずっとみんな なかよし
but everyone was always close
「苦しい」を 分け合ったとき
When we shared the "pain",
私にもできた 恩返し
I was finally able to return the favor
大事な人
People important to me,
好きな人
people I love,
いつもそばにいてほしい よね。
I want them by my side always, right?
上手に踊ってね
Dance well,
私にしてくれたように
just like you did for me
少しほつれたとことか
Even the parts that are a bit frayed,
めちゃ可愛いね
they're so cute
身体もたくさん
Stitch together
好きに繋ぎ合わせて
many body parts as you like
少し歪だけどね
They're a little distorted, though
大切な家族たちなの
They're my precious family members
ねえ見て お気に入りの
Hey, look at my favorite,
世界に一つの お人形さん
one-of-a-kind doll in the world
顔も性格も 違ったけど
Our faces and personalities were different,
ずっとみんな なかよし
but everyone was always close
なかよし なかよし なかよし
Friends, friends, friends
やさしい うれしい
Kind, happy
たのしい いとしい
Fun, beloved
ほめて なでて
Praise me, pet me
ねえ ねえ ねえ
Hey, hey, hey
上手に踊ってね
Dance well,
私にしてくれたように
just like you did for me
少しほつれたとことか
Even the parts that are a bit frayed,
めちゃ可愛いね
they're so cute
身体もたくさん
Stitch together
好きに繋ぎ合わせて
many body parts as you like
少し歪だけどね
They're a little distorted, though
大切な。
Precious.
たいせつな。
だ い ぜ っ な
P r e c i o u s
家族たちなの
family members
私たち
We...
家族なの
...are family.
生誕ライブ限定グッズ販売のお知らせ!!
Announcement of birthday live limited goods sales!!
家族写真 B2 タペストリー
Family Photo B2 Tapestry
ゴージャスな額縁風デザインと肖像画のような二人がとってもキュート。
The gorgeous frame-style design and the two looking like a portrait are so cute.
お部屋の壁に、今日の思い出を飾って彩り豊かな推し活ができちゃいます。
Decorate your room wall with today's memories for a colorful fan life.
おでかけちゃまぬいぐるみ
Outing-Chama Plushie
ボタン風の目がとっても可愛いぬいぐるみ。
A very cute plushie with button-like eyes.
丁寧にひとつひとつ再現されたドレス衣装のちゃまと一緒にお出かけして旅に出れちゃいます。
Go on a trip together with Chama in her dress outfit, carefully reproduced one by one.
鞄に付けれるハートチャーム付き。
Comes with a heart charm that can be attached to a bag.
タランちゃまぬいぐるみポーチ
Taran-Chama Plushie Pouch
あのタランちゃまがポーチに!?
That Taran-Chama is now a pouch!?
背中のファスナーが開いて収納できる便利アイテム。
A convenient item with a zipper on the back for storage.
ゴスロリ衣装のタランちゃまが可愛すぎる!
Taran-Chama in a Gothic Lolita outfit is just too cute!
チェーンがついてるから安心してお外にお散歩させられるよ!
Since it has a chain, you can take her for a walk outside with peace of mind!
タランちゃまスマホリング
Taran-Chama Smartphone Ring
スマホの落下はタランちゃまにお任せ!
Leave preventing smartphone drops to Taran-Chama!
しっかり張り付いて守ってくれます!
She'll stick firmly and protect it!
愛くるしいお目目とつい目が合っちゃう瞬間も癒されてたまりません。
The moments when you accidentally lock eyes with those adorable eyes are irresistibly healing.
全部セットは数量限定もあります。
Full sets also have limited quantities.
フルセット購入特典の数量限定バージョンは、
The limited quantity version of the full set bonus
箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードと、
includes a postcard with a foil-stamped message,
赤井はあと直筆サイン、
Akai Haato's autograph,
特典ボイス『ひみつのはなし』もあるよ。
and even a bonus voice 'Secret Story'.
PRカードもあるよ。
There's even a PR card.
ホロライブ公式ECサイトで販売中!
Now on sale at the Hololive official EC site!
この物語はフィクションであり、登場する人物・団体・はあと様等とは一切関係ありません。
This story is fiction and has no relation to any real people, groups, or Haato-sama.